Finding Aid for Dept. of History (University of Michigan) records, 1884-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Graduate Program
  - Course Enrollment Privileges, 1976 (Box 11)
  - Doctor of Arts, 1969-1978 (Box 11)
  - Doctoral Prelims Sample Questions, undated (Box 11)
  - Extension Service, 1979-1981 (Box 11)
  - Graduate Employee Organization, 1975 (Box 11)
  - Graduate Employees Organization Grievances, 1975-1988 (Box 11)
  - Graduate History Club, 1972-1976 (Box 11)
  - List of Students, 1884-1964; 1987-1988 (Box 11)
  - Minority Recruitment, 1976-1979 (Box 11)
  - Rackham, 1980-1983 (Box 11)
  - Rackham Executive Board Minutes, 1987-1990 (Box 11)
  - Rackham Loan Program, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Rackham Review Committee, 1974-1975; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Student Association, 1973; 1977-1978 (Box 11)
  - Student Fees, 1970-1978 (Box 11)
  - Student Files, 1974-1975 (Box 11)
  - Student Strike, 1975 (Box 11)
  - Student Strike Contingency Plan, 1976 (Box 11)
  - Survey, 1952; 3 folders (Box 11)
- International Relations
  The International Relations series (1950-1998) includes information regarding various international institutions that the Department of History had dealings with, as well as the faculty that came on exchange programs to the University of Michigan.
  - American Research Institute in Turkey, 1988 (Box 12)
  - Burgeura, Monica from Spain, 1998 (Box 12)
  - Cuba Travel, 1996 (Box 12)
  - Freiburg University, 1983 (Box 12)
  - French Faculty Exchange, 1977 (Box 12)
  - Fulbright, Zarine Cooper from India, 1989 (Box 12)
  - Himka, John-Paul from Canada, 1984 (Box 12)
  - International Center, 1978-1981 (Box 12)
  - International Studies, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Japanese Studies Center, 1978-1983 (Box 12)
  - Luff, Peter Albert from the United Kingdom, 1981-1982 (Box 12)
  - Netherlands Visiting Professorship, 1950-1960 (Box 12)
  - Walicki, Adrzej from Australia, 1981-1984 (Box 12)
  - Western European Studies Center, 1969-1986 (Box 12)
- Lecture Series
  The Lecture Series (1977-1987) contains planning regarding the regularly scheduled lecture series held by the Department of History. Included are schedules of events and information regarding each individual that was asked to be a part of the lecture series.
  - Appointment of Lecturers, 1978 (Box 12)
  - Department Lecture Fund, 1978-1980 (Box 12)
  - Hafter, Monroe, 1980 (Box 12)
  - Jerome Lecture Series, 1977-1979 (Box 12)
  - Lecturers, 1986-1987 (Box 12)
  - Long-Term Lecture Proposal, 1978 (Box 12)
  - Request for Lecturers, 1977-1980 (Box 12)
  - Visiting Lecturers, 1977-1979 (Box 12)
- Partner Institutions
  The Partner Institutions series (1946-1994) contains information on organizations and institutions, both within the University of Michigan and outside of it, which the Department of History associated with.
  - Art Museum, 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Babbage Institute, 1979-1980 (Box 12)
  - Center for Continuing Education for Women, 1973-1975 (Box 12)
  - Center for Research on Learning and Teaching (CRLT), 1971-1994; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Institute of Gerontology, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Institute of Historical Research, 1988 (Box 12)
  - Library, 1946 (Box 12)
  - Organization of American Historians, 1958-1973 (Box 12)
  - Palo Alto Center, 1981-1983 (Box 12)
  - School of Education, 1980 (Box 12)
  - Virginia State College -- Michigan Cooperative, 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Washtenaw Community College, 1987 (Box 12)
- Programs
  The Programs series (1970-1996) contains files about various programs that the Department of History participated in or sponsored, such as the Visiting Professor Program, the Sarah Lawrence Program, and the Inteflex Program.
  - American Institutions, 1980-1982 (Box 12)
  - Comparative Literature, 1977-1979 (Box 12)
  - Film and Video Studies, 1995-1996 (Box 12)
  - Honors, Independent Summer Reading, 1970-1974 (Box 12)
  - InteFlex Program, 1972-1986 (Box 12)
  - King/Chvez/Parks Visiting Professor Program, 1988-1989 (Box 12)
  - Michigan Scholars, undated (Box 12)
  - Sarah Lawrence Program, 1978 (Box 12)
- Publications
  The Student Affairs series (1941-1986) contains topical files relating to enrollment in the Department of History. Also included are files regarding admissions information, class schedules, and grading procedures.
  - British Studies Newsletter, 1993-1996 (Box 12)
  - Brochures, 1969; 1972-1973; 1976-1977 (Box 12)
  - Department Newsletter, 1952-2004; 2006-2008; 2010-2011; 8 folders (Box 12)
  - Email Printout, 1997 (Box 12)
  - Flyers, undated; 1987; 1989; 1994-1996; 1999; 2001 (Box 12)
  - Graduate Program Bulletin, 1980-1981; 1983-1989; 1992-1995 (Box 13)
  - Graduate Program Calendar, 1996-2001 (Box 13)
  - Michigan Journal of History, 2002 (Box 13)
  - Undergraduate Course Bulletin, 1998 (Box 13)
  - Weekly Bulletin, 1993-1996 (Box 13)
- Student Affairs
  - Admissions, 1974-1975; 1986 (Box 13)
  - Admissions Forum, 1974 (Box 13)
  - Admissions Internal Reports, 1967-1974 (Box 13)
  - Black Student Recruitment and Enrollment, 1968-1971; 1986 (Box 13)
  - Counseling, 1972-1973 (Box 13)
  - Course Description Books, 1974-1977 (Box 13)
  - Course Listings, 1979 (Box 13)
  - Courses Offered, 1975-1977 (Box 13)
  - Effect of Increasing Enrollment, 1954 (Box 13)
  - Enrollment, 1968-1973 (Box 13)
  - Enrollment by Field, 1970-1971 (Box 13)
  - Enrollment Information, 1975-1976; 1981 (Box 13)
  - Freshman Seminars, 1977-1978 (Box 13)
  - Grade Complaint Procedures, 1974 (Box 13)
  - Grade Point Averages, 1973-1975 (Box 13)
  - Grading, 1972-1973 (Box 13)
  - Grading, General, 1972-1983 (Box 13)
  - Grievance Procedures for Students, 1972-1979 (Box 13)
  - Honors Program, 1941; 1970-1983; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Incompletes, 1970-1974 (Box 13)
  - Independent Reading, Courses, and Study, 1977-1978 (Box 13)
  - Independent Study, 1977-1979 (Box 13)
  - Orientation Office, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Pass/Fail Grading, 1976 (Box 13)
  - Registration Information, 1968-1969 (Box 13)
  - Residential College, 1966-1973 (Box 13)
  - R.O.T.C. Studies, 1969-1975 (Box 13)
  - Script-Division of Research Development and Administration, 1980 (Box 13)
  - Student Discipline, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Student Employment Program, 1979 (Box 13)
  - Student Records, 1967-1977 (Box 13)
  - Supplementary Grades, 1977 (Box 13)
  - Teacher Preparation Courses, 1971-1973 (Box 13)
  - Undergraduate Advising, 1981 (Box 13)
- University of Michigan
  The University of Michigan series (1969-1994) contains general information regarding the university that is not necessarily explicitly for the Department of History. This includes memos sent from the Dean of the university and information on the humanities division, of which the Department of History is a part of.
  - Associate Vice President Holbrook, Robert, 1981-1983 (Box 13)
  - Humanities Advisory Committee, 1978 (Box 13)
  - Humanities Chairman, 1980-1981 (Box 13)
  - Humanities Lecture Series, 1978 (Box 13)
  - Media Resources Center, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Michigan Scholars, 1969-1977 (Box 13)
  - Occupational Health and Safety Standards, 1975 (Box 13)
  - Office of the Vice President of Research, 1976-1977 (Box 13)
  - President Fleming, Robben, 1973-1975 (Box 13)
  - President Shapiro, Harold, 1980-1987 (Box 13)
  - President's Club, 1977 (Box 13)
  - Society of Fellows, 1970-1979; 1994; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Student Assembly, 1982 (Box 13)
  - U-M Press, 1977 (Box 13)
  - University Regulations and Procedures, 1969-1972; 1974-1976 (Box 13)
  - Vice President for Academic Affairs Frye, B.E., 1980-1985 (Box 13)
  - Vice President for Academic Affairs Rhodes, Frank, 1974 (Box 13)